ROBEEN R BILLINGS

Olathe, KS 66061

beans.rb@gmail.com 619.249.0209

MECHANICAL, ELECTRICAL & AUTOMATION ENGINEER Deliver Multi-Disciplinary Team Impact | Improve & Implement Efficient Processes for Cost Reduction

Design optimal electrical, electronics and mechanical systems for project schedule. Improve reliability of programmable logic controllers (PLC), electrical systems and mechanical integration to sustain equipment running, maximize life and capacity of systems. Provide excellent hands on/off troubleshooting and in-depth experience in safety, operations and manufacturing in Naval, Oil & Gas, Airborne and Commercial Industries with background on mechanical, mechatronics, military communications and computer science.

Influencer and mentor with broad background in balancing priorities, identifying the root cause, optimizing reliability, and functioning as a key player in developing and executing repair plan strategies.

Areas of Strength Include:

- Process Improvement, OSHA & Six Sigma
- PLC Systems, Medium and Large Voltage Systems
- Root Cause Failure Analysis
- Equipment Strategy Development
- Maintenance, Scheduling & Planning

- Design Improvement & Sustainability
- Quality Assurance & Troubleshooting
- VFDs, Conveyors, Gearboxes, Motors
- Mentoring, Coaching & Training
- Communication, Customer Service & Team Lead

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

UNITED HEALTH GROUP

Automation Equipment Maintenance

2019-Present

Overland Park, KS

Lead and support emerging electrical, automation and controls equipment repairs, planning and improvements. Provide repair recommendations, equipment modifications to improve reliability and performance.

- Supported the rebuild and implementation of 480V 3phase motors, pumps, pneumatic diverters, hydraulic conveyors, motor control cabinets, relay switches for a new and existing facilities.
- Led root cause failure analysis of 6 high speed printing press and automation machines to prevent reduced rates of process.
- Increased the reliability of 6 high speed printing press and automation machines by identifying the root cause and improve preventing reduced rates of process and reprogramming logic system software.

FEDEX GROUND

Maintenance Lead 2016 – 2019

Hayward, CA; Medley, FL; Lenexa, KS

Lead and support repairs for conveyors, conveyor beds, diverter arms, hydraulics, pulleys, shafts, VFD's, PLCs, programmable logic units. Provide recommendations and risk assessments to ensure continuity and operational success. Performs standard preventative maintenance procedures using maintenance processes and techniques to diagnose and repair of electrical, electronic, mechanical and control systems to maintain the unit running and minimize downtime.

- Earned 2017 and 2018 Recognition Award for achieving step change performance and delivery of technically complete maintenance procedure improvement, repairs and reliability.
- Reprogrammed the diverter PLC by decreasing the diverting time due to volume increase of the assembly line to prevent manufacturing flow backup and shutdown of line.
- Saved \$100K by implementing and improving the performance of conveyor and system minimizing customer delays and outgoing of product by fabricating gravity rollers and install them to prevent conveyor belt to fold over.
- Efficiency of \$30K captured per year by removing bad actor performance of radial signal from extendels and reconfiguring and rewiring the control cabinet to minimize control interruptions and shutdowns.
- Served as sole team lead, supporting execution of maintenance providing technical guidance and preventative maintenance of 10 machines to 5 technicians without safety, reliability, and loss production impact.
- Performed corrective maintenance, emergency maintenance and routine maintenance to understand when each type of maintenance is required to be followed using six sigma improvement processes to capture efficiencies.

ROBEEN BILLINGS beans.rb@gmail.com PAGE TWO

FEDEX GROUND (CONTINUED)

- Updated procedures for assembling 4 including clearances, technical hold points to improve reliability of rebuild and gaps.
- Interfaced directly with FedEx stakeholders, establishing understanding of repair technical hold point gaps, developing inspection/execution strategy, and confirming strategy assumptions.
- Reduced cost by leading multi-disciplinary team in evaluating alternative design for upgrading motor and gearbox bearings, defining right repair scope, gaining engagement from operations, and troubleshooting.

VT GROUP INTEGRATED SOLUTIONS (MILCOM)

Electronic Lead 2015-2016

Jacksonville, FL

Senior Electronic Lead developing strategy and executing removal of military communication for intelligence and communication worldwide. Troubleshoot communications system such as multi-cable transits (MCT), power signal, antenna platforms, aircraft warning lights, waveguide, fiber optics, PCM and RAM material for ships. Under supervision, performs duties involving the installation, maintenance and modification to single channel and multi-channel electronic systems. Provides technical assistance, guidance, or training to technicians.

- Improved safety performance and reliability of equipment functionality reporting, and data trend analysis by efficiently leading execution repairs.
- Provided overhaul scope, equipment condition monitoring, equipment start-up support, quality assurance of repairs for more than 100 ships.
- Performed contract projects with more than 15 customers to improve and upgrade communications systems including logics, troubleshooting, providing update reports for customer and schedule to meet customer's needs.
- Performed installations, maintenance, and troubleshoot systems including relay logic, ladder diagrams, control components, photo eyes, motor starters, relays, limit switches, proximity sensors, timers, solenoids, and other systems.

RELATED EXPERIENCE

RADIANT SYSTEMS INC, Menlo Park, CA Electronics, SLAC National Accelerator Laboratory	2018
AMAZON, Ruskin, FL Industrial Maintenance, Maintenance Department	2015
HONEYWELL, Jacksonville, FL Electronics Technician, Communications	2015
VISION INC L-3 COMMUNICATIONS, Boonton, NJ L-3 Communications and Mobile, Communications Division	2014
UNITED STATES NAVY San Diego, CA Electrical Specialist, C5I	2009

EDUCATION

Associate of Science (AS), Computer Engineering, Essex County College, Newark, NJ

Navy ETA School for Basic Electronics, AC/DC and ETC School for Ultra High Frequency Transceiver Radios, CA

TECHNICAL SKILLS

_	Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint	_	Computer Networking, CAT 6	-	Electrical Safety, Research
-	AC/DC Motors	_	Radio Frequency	-	Advanced System Troubleshooting
-	Calibration & Solution Innovation	-	Gearboxes	-	Integrated & Electronic Circuits
_	Logic & Microprocessor Systems	_	Mechanical & Instrumentation	_	C++ & AutoCAD, Electrical Engineering